准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
情人节
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
情人节快乐  裤头村
Happy Valentine's Day, Bikini Bottom
情人节快乐  海绵宝宝
Happy Valentine's Day, SpongeBob
我用坚果表示对你的爱
I'm nuts for you
那我用泡泡表示对你的爱  珊迪
Well, I'm bubbles for you, Sandy
巧克力糖浆
巧克力
Chocolate
可好吃了
Mighty tasty
派大星肯定会爱上
Patrick's going to love
你亲手给他做的巧克力
the one you made for him
帮我再过一遍计划吧
Take me through the plan again
好
Okay
第一步
Step one
我和派大星抵达情人节嘉年华
Patrick and I get to the Valentine's Day carnival
第二步
Step two
我把派大星和我自己
I position Patrick and myself
安顿在摩天轮顶端
on top of the Ferris wheel
第三步
Step three
你抵达指定的确认地点
you arrive at designated checkpoint
确保取得最大视觉接触
for maximum visual contact
第四步
Step four
派大星很兴奋
Patrick is thrilled
任务完成
Mission accomplished
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
你好
Hello?
派大星
Patrick
是我  海绵宝宝
it's me, SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  你在里面干什么
SpongeBob, what are you doing in there?
派大星
Patrick
我的天啊
Oh my gosh
海绵
Sponge
海绵宝宝被困在石头里面了
SpongeBob is stuck inside this rock
撑住  兄弟
Hold on, buddy
我来救你出来
I'll get you out
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
派大星
Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
派大星  我就在你身后
Patrick, I'm right behind you
你在这啊
There you are
情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's Day
这是你的礼物
Here's your present
我也有份礼物要送你
And I have a present for you
真的
You do?
这可是最棒的
It's the greatest
最最好的
The bestest
最绝最妙的
The most fantabulous
超棒好礼物
Present ever
不过礼物现在还不能到你手上
But you can't have it yet
为什么
Why not?
因为还没准备好
'Cause it's not ready yet
现在准备好了吗
Is it ready now?
还没
Not yet
那现在呢
How about now?
你是想破坏惊喜吗
Do you want to ruin the surprise?
想
Yes
求你快说吧
Come on, please
不行  抱歉
Nope, sorry
你一定要说出来
You got to tell me
行不通
No can do
你只能等着了
You'll just have to wait
求你
Please
跟我说
Tell me
求你了
Please
好了派大星  我们到了
Okay, Patrick, here we are
你送我一个嘉年华
You got me a carnival?
我的了
Mine
全是我的
All mine
情人节嘉年华
我的
mine
好了  大家都出去
All right, everybody out
这是我的嘉年华
This is my carnival
礼物不是嘉年华
It's not the carnival
给  要不你就收下这两毛五再
Here, why don't you take this quarter and
我的天啊  两毛五
Oh my gosh, a quarter
我一直都很想要这两毛五
I've always wanted a quarter
不是这两毛五
It's not the quarter
快拿着这两毛五去买点棉花糖吧
Now take that quarter and buy some cotton candy
棉花糖  我真不敢相信
Cotton candy, I can't believe it
棉花糖
Cotton candy
快走开
Get away
珊迪呼叫海绵宝宝
Sandy to SpongeBob
请回答  海绵宝宝
Come in, SpongeBob
收到珊迪  我是海绵宝宝
Ten-four, Sandy, SpongeBob here
我已看到嘉年华
I got a visual on the carnival
要让我把巧克力带进来吗
You want me to bring her in?
先别进来  珊迪
Not yet, Sandy
派大星还在猜他情人节礼物是什么
Patrick's still trying to guess what his valentine is
你可真会逗人家
You are such a kidder
珊迪完毕
Sandy out
那个海绵宝宝啊
That SpongeBob
扇贝
Scallops
吃巧克力的扇贝
Chocolate-eating scallops
那如果不是棉花糖的话  会是什么
So if it's not cotton candy, then what is it?
我受不了了
I can't take it
你得猜猜
You'll have to guess
鱼太太算命
这顶帐篷
This tent
不对
No
旋转爱心
这个人
This guy?
不对
No
这只草履虫
This paramecium?
不对
Nope
你可真是狡猾
You're a sly one
之所以我在嘉年华里头找不到礼物
I can't find it here in the carnival
是因为礼物在爬上去摔下来山顶上
because it's on top of mount climb-up-and-fall-off
礼物也不在那
It wasn't there, either
你确定吗
Are you sure?
珊迪呼叫海绵宝宝
Sandy to SpongeBob
海绵宝宝呼叫珊迪
SpongeBob to Sandy
可以把礼物带进来了
You can bring it in now
海绵宝宝  我这出了点小问题
SpongeBob, we've got ourself a little problem
我这有一群吃巧克力的扇贝
I got a pack of chocolate-eating scallops
想要盗走气球
trying to rustle the balloon
快走开  爱吃甜食的害虫
Get away, you sweet-toothed varmints
我可能会晚一些到
I'm going to be a little late
晚一些
Late?
可是怎么处理
But what about
派大星
Patrick?
把他带到摩天轮顶端
Take him up to the Ferris wheel
我在那跟你会合
and I'll meet you there
珊迪完毕
Sandy out
要是派大星收不到情人节礼物
If Patrick doesn't get his valentine
我很确定礼物不在那上面  海绵宝宝
I'm pretty sure it's not up there, SpongeBob
派大星
Patrick
其实是在摩天
Actually it's on the Ferris
摩天轮
Ferris wheel
我现在准备好要收到全世界最棒的
I'm ready for the greatest valentine present
情人节礼物了  海绵宝宝
in the whole world now, SpongeBob
接收礼物的地方就是这了
Well, this is where you're going to get it
希望吧
I hope
一直往那看  兄弟
Just keep looking out there, pal
海绵宝宝呼叫珊迪
SpongeBob to Sandy
请回答  珊迪
Come in, Sandy
珊迪呼叫海绵宝宝
Sandy to SpongeBob
我这边遇上了麻烦
I got my ox in a hitch here
严重偏离航线
I'm way off course
扇贝在吃气球
The scallops are eating the balloon
它们到处都是
They're everywhere
真见鬼
Oh, shoot
就要下坠了  海绵宝宝
We're going down, SpongeBob
执行B计划
Switch to Plan B
不要B计划  珊迪
No B, Sandy
不要B计划
No B
不要
No
派大星
Patrick
你知不知道有时计划一样特别的事情
you know how sometimes you plan something special
结果却又事事不顺吗
and things just don't work out?
不  不
No, no
我的天啊
Holy mackerel
这上边是太热了还是怎么了
Is it hot up here or what?
情人节礼物  情人节礼物
Valentine, valentine
不
No
不  派大星
No, Patrick
情人节
Valentine
派大星  不要
Patrick, don't
情人节
Valentine
派大星
Patrick
礼物在这
Here it is
什么东西
What's that?
是握手  亲切友好的握手
A handshake, a friendly handshake
握手
A handshake?
这就是盛大礼物
That's the big gift?
你就送了我一场握手
You got me a handshake?
是亲切友好的握手
A friendly handshake
情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's Day
超棒好朋友
充气城堡
欢乐屋
我一直在想
I've been thinking
起先一场握手看起来分量并不大
At first a handshake doesn't seem like much
但是
But
真正重要的是你关心我
Really it's the thought that counts
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
我要谢谢你送我这盒巧克力
I just wanted to thank you for this box of chocolates
没问题  弗朗
No problem, Fran
我是说  即使我本来一直在期待更多
I mean, even though I was expecting more
谢谢你送我玫瑰  海绵宝宝
Thanks for the roses, SpongeBob
情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's Day
你也一样  戴夫
You too, Dave
并不是说我们当了这么久的朋友如何
Not that it matters that we've been friends for so long
海绵宝宝  谢谢你送我自行车
Hey, SpongeBob, thanks for the bike
你能相信这家伙吗
Can you believe this guy?
我早上才刚认识他呢
I just met him this morning
所以如我所说
So, as I was saying
不好意思  请问现在几点了
Excuse me, do you guys have the time?
派大星也需要爱
Patrick needs love, too
气球
我要反抗你  爱心人
I defy you, heart man
所有人请注意
Attention, everyone
有一只在逃的粉红胖海星
There's a chubby pink starfish on the loose
爱心棒必须死
Heart on stick must die
派大星
Patrick
把海绵宝宝交出来
Give me SpongeBob
你让我心碎了
You broke my heart
现在我要弄碎你的东西
Now I'm going to break something of yours
好吧  派大星
Okay, Patrick
我知道这是我的报应
I know I deserve this
可他们也得这样吗
but do they?
他们也什么都没给我
They didn't give me anything, either
不行  现在已经太晚了
Nope, it's too late for that now
你们全都太晚了
for all of you
快点走  小贝壳
Get along, little shellfish
快飞  你们这些扇贝
Giddap, you scallops
好耶  珊迪来了
Yeah, Sandy's here
派大星快看  礼物到了
Look, Patrick, it's here
礼物到了
It's here
全世界最棒的情人节礼物
The best valentine in the whole wide world
就在你身后
is right behind you
确实
Sure it is
我跟你说它就在那
I'm telling you it's right there
快转身
Turn around
派大星  转个身
Patrick, just turn around
转身
Turn around
大笨蛋  快转身
Hey, nincompoop, turn around
你们肯定觉得我很笨是吧
You must think I'm pretty dumb, huh?
对
Yes
快转身
Turn around
不行
No
转身  转身
Turn around, turn around
我就再说这么一次
I'm going to say this once
而且这也是最后一次
and I'm not going to say it again
都注意好了
so pay attention
我不会
I am not
重复
I repeat
不会再因为任何原因转过身去
not going to turn around for any reason ever
你好  派大星
Howdy, Patrick
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
情人节快乐  派大星
Happy Valentine's Day, Patrick
我的情人节礼物
My valentine
这是巧克力吗
Is this solid chocolate?
派大星  不
Patrick, no
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你没必要什么都给我
you didn't have to give me anything
纸
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
该放松了
Time to relax
章鱼哥
Squidward
好了  该走了
Well, time to go
章鱼哥
Squidward
章鱼哥  等等
Squidward, wait
又怎么了
Now what?
你掉了这张纸
You dropped this piece of paper
是啊  所以怎么了
Yeah, so what?
我只是觉得你可能会想要回来
I just figured you probably want it back
这又有什么大不了的
What's the big deal?
就一垃圾罢了
It's only garbage
垃圾
Garbage?
可是章鱼哥
But, Squidward
如果交给正确的人手上
in the right hands
这张纸就会成为充满着休闲娱乐的金矿
this paper is a gold mine of entertainment
一整个精彩下午的海底乐趣
A spectacular afternoon of underwater fun
充满着财宝的
A treasure trove of
垃圾
Garbage
所以你不要了
So you don't want it?
对
Right
是不是表示我可以收下了
Does that mean I can have it?
对  当然可以
Yes, by all means
快收下
take it
喂
Hello
确定吗
You sure?
对
Yes
再说最后一次  我不要那破纸
For the final time, I don't want that paper
以后永远都是你的
It's yours forever and ever
所以你十分确定以及肯定吗
So are you definitely, positively sure?
出去
Get out
可是你
But are you
出
Get
去
out
最后一次反悔的机会了  章鱼哥
Last chance to change your mind, Squidward
你快收下  海绵宝宝
Take it, SpongeBob
快给我收下
Take it, please
并且向我保证
And promise me
无论我怎么向你求向你要向你哭
no matter how much I may beg and plead and cry
都别把那纸还给我
don't give that paper back to me ever
所以就当这是不要了
So I take that as a possible no?
章鱼哥
Squidward?
好吧  章鱼哥
Okay, Squidward
就这么说定了  我只能把纸留下了
that's a promise, I'll just have to keep
啊  纸先生
Ah, Mr. Paper
我好幸运能有章鱼哥那样的朋友
I am so lucky to have a friend like Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你到底是在笑什么笑
What in the world are you giggling about?
对不起  章鱼哥
I'm sorry, Squidward
只是
it's just
只是我在想
It's just that I'm thinking of
我用这张纸的能弄出来的所有玩法
all the fun I'm going to have with this piece of paper
怎么会有人能玩一张纸
How can anyone have fun with just a piece of paper?
他用那破纸能玩出什么花样来
What can he possibly be doing with that paper?
小蜗  看好了
Gary, watch this
猜猜我是啥
Guess what I am?
答对了  小蜗
Well, yes, Gary
我是裤子里卡了纸的海绵
I am a sponge with paper stuck in his pants
但我还是吸干犯罪的超级海绵
but I'm also super sponge soaking up crime
看吧  这是我的斗篷
See, here's my cape
超级白痴还差不多
Super moron's more like it
现在我是丛林宝宝
Now I'm SpongeBob JunglePants
天啊
Oh, boy
丛林宝宝呼唤动物伙伴
SpongeBob JunglePants summon animal friends
你说得对  小蜗
You're right, Gary
我不是丛林小子
I'm not a jungle boy
我是一箱军需物资
I am a box of army supplies
为饥饿的士兵们带来援助
Bringing relief to the hungry troops
着陆及时  刚好能赶上
Landing just in time for
斗牛赛
The bullfight
冲啊
Toro
冲啊  小蜗
Toro, Gary
公牛冲啊
Toro, toro
冲啊
Toro
小蜗
Gary
冲啊
Toro
好耶
Hey, ole
来做滑稽表演
Now for some impressions
长胡子的人
a guy with a mustache
快看我  我是长胡子的人
Look at me, I'm a guy with a mustache
戴眼罩的海盗
A pirate with an eye patch
啊  我是海盗
Arr, I'm a pirate
戴眼罩的普通人
A regular guy with an eye patch
啊  我不是海盗
Arr, I am not a pirate
干脆扮个拿着破纸的黄色大白痴好了
Do a big yellow idiot with a stupid piece of paper
他是怎么做到的
How did he do that?
你看  小蜗
Look, Gary
嚼纸
Oral-gami
鸟
Bird
雪花
Snowflake
纸片人
Paper doll
那小纸片好像还挺好玩
That little paper does seem like fun
我在说什么
What am I saying?
我可真是个白痴
I am such an idiot
说真的  海绵宝宝跟他那张破纸
SpongeBob, honestly, and his dumb paper
管那叫好玩
He calls that fun?
来看点无聊科学文摘  这才叫好玩
Now reading boring science digest, that's fun
无聊科学
来看看腐蚀
Check erosion
有丝分裂
Mitosis
快看  我连洗澡都玩得很开心
See, I can have fun taking a bath
画水果
Painting fruit--
画水果最最好玩了
There's nothing more fun than painting fruit
比什么都好玩
This is more fun than anything
我要向他证明那张纸一点都不好玩
I'll prove to him that paper is not fun
我在玩
I'm having fun
棒不棒
Isn't it great
好了海绵宝宝  来超越我这个
Okay, SpongeBob, top this one
小章鱼哥
Hey, little Squidward
什么东西又灰又丑  还长着六条胳膊
what's gray and ugly and has six arms?
我不知道  可是你照过镜子了没
I don't know, but have you looked in the mirror lately?
什么
What?
你怎么
Why you
真好笑  章鱼哥
That's a good one, Squidward
来让我试试
now let me try
你听过什么好笑话吗  纸先生
Have you heard any good jokes, Mr. Paper?
纸掉进海里出了什么事
What happened to the paper that fell in the ocean?
不知道
I don't know
纸掉进海里出了什么事
What happened to the paper that fell in the ocean?
全都泡汤了
It was all washed-up
我玩新买的贝壳车玩得好开心
I'm having so much fun with my new shell cart
海绵宝宝  你的破纸能这样吗
Hey, SpongeBob, can your stupid paper do this?
不能
Nope
你用一张纸演奏不出音乐
Well, you can't play music with a piece of paper
万岁
Hooray
太棒了  章鱼哥
That was great, Squidward
你吹错的所有音
All those wrong notes you played
显得你那曲子更像原创的了
made it sound more original
什么
What?
我没吹错音啊
I didn't play any wrong notes
就错了
Yeah
你看  你是这么吹的
See, you're playing it like this
本来一般要这么吹
When ordinarily it goes like this
我个人更偏向用a小调来吹
I'm partial to doing it in the key of a-minor, myself
朋友之间的双重奏最好不过了
Nothing like a duet between buddies
对吧章鱼哥
eh, Squidward?
快把纸还给我
Give me my paper back
快放手
Now let go of it
我说快放手
I said let go of it
放手
Let go
不行
I can't
你说不行是什么意思
What do you mean you can't?
我不行
I can't
你让我向你保证
You made me promise
无论你怎么向我求向我要向我哭
no matter how much you begged and pleaded and cried
都别把那纸还给你
not to give the paper back to you ever
我可没说过那种话
I never said anything like that
你说过了  章鱼哥
Sure you did, Squidward
你看
Look
你快收下  海绵宝宝
Take it SpongeBob
快给我收下
Take it, please
并且向我保证
And promise me
无论我怎么向你求向你要向你哭
no matter how much I may beg and plead and cry
都别把那纸还给我
don't give that paper back to me ever
要再看一遍吗
Want to see it again?
不要  我不想再看了
No, I don't want to see it again
把纸还给我
Just give me that paper
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squidward
我一定要信守承诺
I am sworn to a promise
也许我该走了
Maybe I should get going
等等  等等
Wait, wait
我们应该可以拿东西做交换
maybe we can trade for something
对
Yeah
东西  东西
something, something
等下  海绵宝宝
Wait up, SpongeBob
等等
Wait
别走  兄弟
Hold on there, chum
我来给你出个价
I'm going to make you an offer
口袋漏出来的绒毛
Pocket lint
你可真会讨价还价  章鱼哥
You drive a hard bargain, Squidward
拿纸换绒毛
Paper for lint
不是绒毛  是橡皮筋
Not the lint, the rubber band
橡皮筋
The rubber band?
我该换吗
Do I dare?
换
Dare
好
Okay
我明白了
I get it
你是在考验我
You're just testing me
你放心  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我不会让你失望了
I won't let you down
保证就是保证
A promise is a promise
你给我听好
Listen, you
不达成交易你哪都别想去
you are not going anywhere until we strike a deal
一定要弄到
Got to get that
纸
paper
章鱼哥
Squidward?
交易
Trade
跟你说
Listen
所有东西都
Everything must
给你
go
那是我最后的家当了
Well, that's the last of it
除了我穿的衬衣  其他东西都给你了
I've given you everything but the shirt off my back
章鱼哥  这是不是还是考验的一部分
Squidward, is this still part of the test
因为
'cause it's
信守承诺真的越来越难了
It's really getting harder and harder
to keep my promise
好  衬衣
Okay, the shirt
收下  收下我的衬衣
Take it, take my shirt
章鱼哥的衬衣
Squidward's shirt
我一直都好爱那件衬衣
I've always loved that shirt
好  好
Okay, okay
会交易的
I'll trade
我会为了这个打破诺言
I can break a promise for this
章鱼哥  你其他东西要不要拿回去
Squidward, do you want your other stuff
因为我只要这件衬衣
'cause this is all I'll need
那堆垃圾全归你了  因为我有这个了
You can have all that junk 'cause now I've got this
我有了纸
I've got the paper
你有我没用的垃圾
and you've got my useless garbage
到手了
I got it
你弄不到
You can't have it
到手了  你是个白痴
I got it, you're a sucker
你是个白痴
You're a sucker
终于啊
At last
我们该先来做什么  纸先生
What should we try first, Mr. Paper?
滑稽表演
Impressions
一个人把一张纸放在鼻子上
A guy with a piece of paper on his nose
快看我  我一个人把一张纸
Look at me, I'm a guy with a piece of paper
放在
on his
鼻子上
nose
等下
Wait
烂
Boo
好好
Okay, okay
直升机
Helicopter
先生们  启动引擎
Gentlemen, start your engines
我在飞了
I'm flying
对  我在飞了
Oh, yeah, I'm flying
我在飞了
I'm flying
没错  没错
That's right, that's right
我们出发
here we go now
我在飞  在飞
I'm flying, flying
等下  更多滑稽表演
Wait, more impressions
一个人把一张纸狠狠扔在地上
A guy throwing a piece of paper on the ground
一个人用脚踩这张纸
A guy stomping on the piece of paper
我把所有家当都换成了
I'm a guy who traded everything he owns for
一张没用的纸
A worthless piece of paper
谢谢
Thanks
我要的就是这个  章鱼哥
it's just what I needed, Squidward
衬衣不错  海绵宝宝
Nice shirt, SpongeBob
有人有防晒霜吗
Does anybody have any sunscreen?